Guide to the Department of French, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- French sound archives collected by Pierre Capretz, 1959-1983; Accession 2001-A-152
  - Juliette Greco
    - Side 1
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
    - Side 2
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
      - 1983 February 18 (Box 41)
  - Demonstration tapes
    - DM-1-1 Orientation program, 1971 September (Box 41)
    - DM-1-2 MMP I (Box 41)
    - DM-1-3 MMP II (Box 41)
    - DM-1-4 Description of lab (Box 41)
    - DM-1-5 Description of Lab, MMP's, Testing, 1976 (Box 41)
    - DM-1-6 Existentialisme: Vocabulary Demo (Box 41)
    - DM-1-7 Capretz: Use of film in foreign language teaching (Box 41)
    - DM-1-8 Capretz: Announcement for the International Convention On Use of Technology in Foreign Language Teaching (Box 41)
  - Duplicates
    - F-O-114 (Box 41)
    - F-O-12 (Box 41)
    - F-O-32 (Box 41)
    - F-O-33 (Box 41)
    - F-O-35 (Box 42)
    - F-O-81 to 82 (2 tapes) (Box 42)
    - F-O-100 (Box 42)
    - F-O-108 (Box 42)
    - F-O-120 (Box 42)
    - F-O-140 (Box 42)
    - F-O-185 (Box 42)
    - F-O-199 to 203 (2 tapes) (Box 42)
    - F-O-216 (Box 42)
    - F-O-257 (Box 42)
    - F-O-331/333 (Box 42)
    - F-O-392-5 (2 tapes) (Box 42)
    - F-O-418 to 421 (11 tapes) (Box 42)
    - F-O-432 to 433 (2 tapes) (Box 42)
    - F-O-456 (Box 42)
    - F-O-478 to 479 (2 tapes) (Box 42)
    - F-O-480 (Box 42)
    - F-O-480 (Box 43)
    - F-O-40 to 42 (3 tapes) (Box 43)
    - F-O-817 (Box 43)
    - F-O-961 (Box 43)
    - F-O-355 (Box 43)
    - F-O-482 (Box 43)
    - F-O-548 (Box 43)
    - F-O-551 to 554 (Box 43)
    - F-O-556 to 558 (2 tapes) (Box 43)
    - F-O-571 to 573 (3 tapes) (Box 43)
    - F-O-591 to 592 (Box 43)
    - F-O-595 to 596 (Box 43)
    - F-O-634 (Box 43)
    - F-O-662 TO 663 (2 tapes) (Box 43)
    - F-O-668 (Box 43)
    - F-O-691 (Box 43)
    - F-O-697 to 698 (2 tapes) (Box 43)
    - F-O-704 to 707 (4 tapes) (Box 43)
    - F-O-766 to 768 (2 tapes) (Box 43)
    - F-O-764 (Box 43)
    - F-O-770 to 771 (Box 44)
    - F-O-776 to 779 (Box 44)
    - F-O-827 (Box 44)
    - F-O-829 to 831 (3 tapes) (Box 44)
    - F-O-838 (Box 44)
    - F-O-845 (Box 44)
    - F-O-850 to 851 (2 tapes) (Box 44)
    - F-O-1055 (Box 44)
    - F-O-34 (Box 44)
    - Excerpts (2 tapes) (Box 44)
  - Office de Radiodiffusion Television Francaise (32 vinyl record albums, in approximate range of F-O-1201 to 1304 (Box 45)
- Videotapes and films documenting French language instruction at Yale, Undated; Accession 2001-A-153
  - Boorsch/Capretz. Méthode de Francais. Lessons 1-24, F-V-125 to 159, 24 (Box 1)
  - Boorsch/Capretz. New methods for teaching languages, 4 (Box 1)
- Audiotapes (reel-to-reel) of teaching materials, Accession 2001-A-154
  - F-1-13 to F-1-29, Leon: Lessons 1-16, 17 (Box 1)
  - F-1-30 to 42 Lecon, Lessons 1-34, 13 (Box 4)
  - F-1-43 Lecon, Lessons 1 and 2, 1 (Box 4)
  - F-1-44, Lecon, Lessons 3 and 4, 1 (Box 1)
  - F-1-45 to 48 Lecon, Lesson 5-11, 4 (Box 4)
  - F-1-49 Pronunciation Drill 1, 1 (Box 4)
  - F-1-50 to 56 Delattre, Lessons 1-9, 7 (Box 4)
  - F-1-59 to 66 Delattre, Lessons 10-17, 8 (Box 5)
  - F-1-67 to 69 BEL Enchantillonage phonétique, 3 (Box 5)
  - F-1-70 to 72 BEL Les Possessifs francais, 3 (Box 5)
  - F-1-73 to 74 BEL Il faut", 2 (Box 5)
  - F-1-176 to 192, Lecon: Improving Oral Pronunciation, Units 1-17, 17 (Box 5)
  - F-1-193 to 205, Lecon: Improving Oral Pronunciation, Units 18-30, 13 (Box 2)
  - F-1-176 to 205 Improving French pronunciation, 9 (Box 2)
  - F-1-206 to 218 Callamand: L'Intonation Expressive, Lessons 1-13, 13 (Box 2)
  - F-1-219 to 225 Callamand: L'Intonation Expressive, Lessons 14-20, 7 (Box 3)
  - F-1-567 F15 Boorsch: Methode orale, 1964-1965; 1 (Box 3)
  - F-1-578 to 579 F15/25 Methode Orale", 1966-1967; 2 (Box 3)
  - F-1-580 F 18 Boorsch: lesson 7, 1965-1966; 1 (Box 3)
  - F-1-115-1 to 4 Boorsch and Capretz: Methode de Francais I, 4 (Box 4)
  - F-1-115-5 to 8, 10-14, 16-29, 31 Boorsch and Capretz: Méthode de Francais I, 24 (Box 3)
  - F-1-153 to 161 French Diction for Singers, Lessons 1-9, 9 (Box 4)
  - French 130
    - F130-1 to 5 Sartre: Huis-Clos, 5 (Box 11)
    - F130-6 to 8 Camus: L'Hote, 3 (Box 11)
    - F130-9 to 23 Camus: L'Etranger, 15 (Box 11)
    - F130-24 to 27 Giraudoux: L'Apollon de Bellac, 4 (Box 11)
    - F130-28 to 35 Truffaut: Jules et Jim, 8 (Box 11)
    - F130-36 to 37 Ionesco: La Cantatrice Chauve", 2 (Box 11)
    - F130-38-to 39 Ionesco: La Cantatrice Chauve", 2 (Box 10)
    - F130-40 Apollinaire: Saint Adorata, 1 (Box 10)
    - F130-50 to 58 Gide la Symphonie Pastorale", 2 (Box 10)
    - F130-59 to 62 Sartre: La Chambre, 4 (Box 10)
    - F130-63 to 69 Melville: Le Doulos, 7 (Box 10)
    - F130-70 to 72 Ionesco: La Lecon, 3 (Box 10)
    - F130-73 Barthes: Le bifteck frites, 1 (Box 10)
    - F130-74 Barthes: Le vin et le lait, 1 (Box 10)
    - F130-74 and 80 Mauriac: Therese Desqueyroux, 6 (Box 10)
    - F130-83 and 85 Truffaut: Tirez sur le Pianiste, 3 (Box 10)
    - F130-81 and 82 Duhamel: L'Epave", 2 (Box 9)
    - F130-86 to 87 Truffaut: Tirez sur le Pianiste", 2 (Box 9)
    - F130-88 to 92, 5 (Box 9)
    - F130-100 to 127 Grammar, 29 (Box 9)
    - F130-128 to 142 Grammar, 15 (Box 8)
    - F130-200 to 223 Grammar, 24 (Box 8)
    - F130-224 Grammar, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-800 to 804 Grammar, 5 (Box 6)
    - F130-225 Grammar, 1 (Box 6)
    - F130-227 to 239 Grammar, 13 (Box 6)
    - F130-805 to 812 Review, 8 (Box 6)
    - F130-818 La Famille, 1 (Box 6)
    - F130-820 L'Education, 1 (Box 6)
    - F130-900 to 905, 6 (Box 6)
    - F130-906 to 907, 2 (Box 7)
    - F130-1100, 1 (Box 7)
    - F13-1102 to 1104, 3 (Box 7)
    - F130-1106, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-1109 to 1111, 3 (Box 7)
    - F130-1113, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-1115 to 1117, 3 (Box 7)
    - F130-1119, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-1122 to 1123, 2 (Box 7)
    - F130-1140, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-1203 to 1205, 3 (Box 7)
    - F130-1212, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-2100, audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 7)
    - F130-2103 to 2104, 2 (Box 7)
    - F130-2106, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-2110 to 2111, 2 (Box 7)
    - F130-2115 to 2116, 2 (Box 7)
    - F130-2212, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-3100, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-3103, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-3106, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-3115, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-4100, 1 (Box 7)
    - F130-4103, 1 (Box 7)
- "French in Action" videotapes, Accession 2001-A-155
  - Lessons 3-11 (Box 1)
  - Lessons 13-22 (Box 1)
  - Lesson 24 (Box 1)
  - Lessons 25-27 (Box 2)
  - Lessons 31-39 (Box 2)
  - Lessons 43-52 (Box 2)